(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-27T01:57:51.985702",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
みなさんこんにちは！ときのそらです！
Hello everyone! I'm Tokino Sora!
本日はハッピーバースデー3Dライブです！
Today is my happy birthday 3D live!
ぜひ最後まで楽しんでいってくださいね！
Please enjoy it all the way to the end!
ほらほらまた始まった
Look, look, it's starting again—
お得意の自己弁護言い訳「でもね」「だって」
your trusty self-defense excuses: "But hey", "That said..."
ほらほらまた始まった
Look, look, it's starting again—
ごめん！からのキスのパターンって感じ？安易
"Sorry!" followed by a kiss? So predictable.
「いつかあたしだけ」そんな夢見たこともあったけど
"Someday I'll be the only one"—I've dreamed of that before, but...
寂しい時だけ電話してももううんざりだわ！
Calling only when you're lonely? I'm so sick of it!
全然あたしに興味ないじゃん
You're not interested in me at all.
キミが好きなのは自分でしょう？ (yeah!)
You only love yourself, don't you? (Yeah!)
やっぱりあたしに興味ないじゃん
Seriously, you're not interested in me at all.
その話もう聞き飽きたわ
I'm already sick of hearing that talk.
そもそもだいたいあたしに興味ないじゃん
Above all, you're mostly not interested in me.
そうやってまた誤魔化して… (もうっ！)
Sweeping it under the rug again... (Geez!)
be my boy わがまますぎる baby
Be my boy, you're way too selfish, baby.
抱きしめてよね！
Hold me close!
ホントキミはしょうがないな
Honestly, you're hopeless.
あたしもしょうがないな
Well, I suppose I am too.
泣いていかないでって言って
Saying "Don't leave me crying,"
言ったって変わっちゃくれないよ
won't change a single thing!
もう少しだけならまあ踊ってもいいかもな
Well, I might dance with you a little longer.
とろけとろけイキたいの
I want to melt away completely.
会いに来て
Come see me!
全然あたしに興味ないじゃん
You're not interested in me at all.
どこがダメなの？教えてよ (yeah!)
What's wrong with me? Tell me! (Yeah!)
やっぱりあたしに興味ないじゃん
Seriously, you're not interested in me at all.
携帯ばかりいじってさ
Always fiddling with your phone.
そもそもだいたいあたしに興味ないじゃん
Above all, you're mostly not interested in me.
少しぐらい期待させて (もう…)
At least give me some hope... (Geez...)
lonely girl 独り占めしてよ baby
Lonely girl, keep me all to yourself, baby.
振り回さないで！
Don't run me around!
ねえ？ maybe melty？
Hey? Maybe melty?
ワン・ツー shall we dance? 踊りましょう
One, two, shall we dance? Let's dance.
be my boy わがまますぎる baby
Be my boy, you're way too selfish, baby.
踊りましょう
Let's dance together!
早くて硬く繋いで最後にひとつだけ溺れるくらい愛してよ
Hold my hand tightly and love me until we drown in it at the very end!
全然あたしに興味ないじゃん
You're not interested in me at all.
キミが好きなのは自分でしょう？ (yeah!)
You only love yourself, don't you? (Yeah!)
やっぱりあたしに興味ないじゃん
Seriously, you're not interested in me at all.
その話もう聞き飽きたわ
I'm already sick of hearing that talk.
そもそもだいたいあたしに興味ないじゃん
Above all, you're mostly not interested in me.
そうやってまた誤魔化しても
Even if you brush it off like that...
察する覚悟はできてるの？
Are you prepared to read between the lines?
気まぐれメルシィ 終わりはいかが？
Kimagure Mercy, how is the end?
はい、ということで、始まりましたー！
Hi, and so, it has started!
お誕生日ライブ1曲目から踊り食い…踊り食いの曲を踊ってみました。
For my birthday live, starting with the first song, I danced to... a dancing-while-eating song.
どうでしたでしょうか？
How was it?
本日は来てくれてありがとうございます。
Thank you so much for coming today.
あっ、ぴちぴちありがとうございます！
Ah, pichi-pichi, thank you!
たくさんの人に見てもらえて、とっても嬉しいです。
I'm so happy so many people got to see it.
ちょっと、喉が乾きますね。飲み物飲んできますね。
My throat is getting a bit dry. I'm going to go grab a drink.
というわけで、今回は、ふふ、あの、ね、やっぱり素敵に行きたいなと思っておりますので、ぜひぜひよろしくお願いします。
So this time, um, you know, I really want it to be wonderful, so I hope you'll look forward to it.
そしてね、また途中には、えー、お披露目もございますので、
And also, midway through, um, there's also a reveal, so
楽しんでいっていただけたら嬉しいなと思います！やったー！
I'd be happy if you could enjoy it! Yay!
お水飲んでくるー。
I'm going to go drink some water.
はい、お水は美味しかったよ。
Yep, the water was delicious.
というわけでね、早速一人目のゲスト呼んじゃおうかな？
So, shall we call out our first guest right away?
せーの！はーい！
Ready, go! Yay!
そら先輩、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Sora-senpai, happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
そしてこの場に…
And to be in this place...
これって本当に光栄です。お誘いいただきまして。
it's truly an honor. Thank you for inviting me.
本当にこちらこそありがとうございます！
Thank you so much as well!
ところで、何て呼べばいいですか？
By the way, what should I call you?
おお、実はだって、はい。
Oh, actually, yes.
そうだよね？
That's right, isn't it?
そう、まだしゃべってない方ですもんね。
Right, because we haven't spoken much yet, right?
うんうん。
Uh-huh.
え、なんて呼んでもらおう？
Um, what should you call me?
え、ちょっと、「るいるい」って呼んでもらってもいいですか？
Um, would it be okay if you called me "Ruirui"?
いつも呼びたかったやつだ！嬉しい！
It's what I've always wanted to call you! Yay!
じゃあ今日から私は…あ、私は「るいるい」じゃない。そこにある「るいるい」になっちゃうじゃん！じゃあ「るいるい」って呼びますね！
Then starting today, I am... Ah, I'm not Ruirui. Ah, you'd become the "Ruirui" over there! Then I'll call you Ruirui!
え、お願いします！嬉しい！
Eh, please do! I'm so happy!
いや、本当に嬉しい！
Man, I'm truly so happy!
なんかね、ずっと大空がすごい上手で、よく聞いてたから一緒に歌いたいなって思ってたの。
You know, I've always thought Oozora is so good and listened to you a lot, so I wanted to sing together.
本当に光栄ですよ！
It's truly an honor!
本当に鳥肌立ってる今。ありがとうございます！
I literally have goosebumps right now. Thank you!
いや、こちらこそありがとう！今日一緒に歌えるの本当に楽しみで、昨日夜眠れなくて
No, thank you so much! I was really looking forward to singing together today, I couldn't sleep last night
もう本当に緊張してるんですけど。
and I'm really super nervous right now.
さっきめちゃくちゃご飯めちゃくちゃ食べてて
But earlier you were eating tons of food!
確かに緊張するとご飯も喉を通らないっていうわけではないんで、
True, when you get nervous, it's not like food doesn't go down your throat,
食べようと思って見てて、私。
so I was watching thinking I'd eat.
そら先輩は緊張してたから食べられなかったですか？
Weren't you unable to eat because you were nervous, Senpai?
緊張するとね、なんかね、テンションが上がっちゃって、そうそうそうって言ってね、なんかあんまり、なんていうんだろ
When I get nervous, my tension goes up, and I'm like "yeah yeah yeah", and somehow not, how should I say it,
いや、ソワソワしてる先輩をちょっと間近で見て可愛いなって思ってました。
Well, I was watching you being all restless up close and thought it was cute.
本当？ありがとう！
Really? Thank you!
さあ、そんなね、ルイちゃんとね、ライブしたいんですけど、
Now then, we want to live/sing together with Rui-chan,
その前にちょっとね、なんか付けちゃおうかなって思ってるんです。
but before that, I thought I'd put something on.
お、じゃあつけちゃいます？
Oh, shall we put it on then?
じゃあ私で一旦隠して…てるてるてるてる…たんっ！
Let me hide her for a moment... teruteru... ta-da!
にゃーん！
Meow!
ネコ尻尾もありよ？あれ、なくなっとる！
There's also a cat tail, you know? Oh, it's gone!
なかった！
It wasn't there!
さっきあったのに！
It was just here!
え、なんでないんだ？
Eh? Why isn't it there?
でも、耳がめちゃくちゃ可愛いですね、キュート。カチューシャはつけてます。
But the ears are super cute, cute. I'm wearing the headband.
可愛いですね、可愛い。
So cute, cute.
というわけでね、これをね、つけるとよみたまのこういう感じの曲なんじゃないでしょうかということで、一緒に歌いましょう！
So, if you put this on, isn't it this kind of song from Yomitam? So let's sing together!
はい、ぜひぜひお願いします！
Yes, absolutely please!
それでは聞いてください。
Then please listen.
「嗚呼、素晴らしきニャン生」
"Ah, Wonderful Cat Life"
これは可愛いお嬢さん
Oh, what a lovely princess we have here!
真っ白な毛がとても素敵ね
Fur so pristine and shimmering with care
こんな月が綺麗な夜は 僕と一緒に遊びませんか
Won't you come out the window and play with me tonight?
ニャン生は一度きり 楽しむが勝ちなのです
A cat has only got one life to live, make it meow-velous!
あなたを縛る首輪は 噛み千切ってあげましょう
Shall I tear the collar ’round your neck with my teeth?
野良は最高ニャンニャンニャン♪
Being a stray is great ’cause nyan nyan nyan~
魚くすねて、ハト追いかけて
Stealing fish to eat for meals, chasing pigeons ’round all day
昼間は働く人間を尻目に屋根の上で夢うつつ
Here on the roof I watch the people on their way, drifting off to nap
あなたも自由にニャンニャンニャン♪
You should try it too ’cause nyan nyan nyan~
これは可愛いお嬢さん
What a cute young lady we have here!
真っ白な毛がとても素敵ね
Your pure white fur is so lovely!
こんな月が綺麗な夜は
In this night with such a beautiful moon,
僕と一緒に遊びませんか
Would you like to play together with me?
これは気まぐれな野良猫さん
What a willful stray cat we have here!
闇の中目だけが光っている
Only your eyes are sparkling in the darkness
随分口が上手だけど
You sure know how to talk with that mouth,
私はバカな女じゃないわ
But I am not a dumb lady
ニャン生は一度きり だからこそ飼われるのよ
A cat can only live once, that's why I am kept as a pet
ブランド首輪の価値が あなたには分かるかしら?
Do you even have the faintest idea how much this collar costs?
私は優雅にニャンニャンニャン
I am graceful, meow meow meow
美味しい食事にふかふかベッド
I eat delicious meals and sleep on a fluffy bed
水はちょっと苦手だけど 毎日シャワーだって浴びれるの
Although I slightly dislike water, I still take showers everyday
それに比べてニャンニャンニャン
Compared to me, meow meow meow
あなたは誰に守ってもらうの?
From whom can you seek protection?
明日車に轢かれるかも 知れないじゃない!
Tomorrow, just maybe, you could be run over by a car!
そんな強気なところも素敵です
Your assertive sassiness is charming, too
一層あなたを好きになりました
I'm beginning to take a liking to you
あら正直ね、でもそんなやり方じゃ
Oh my, how blunt, but what you're doing
ココロ揺らがないわ
will not be able to move my heart
僕の夢はニャンニャンニャン
My dream, meow meow meow
いつかはこの街を飛び出して
Is to leap out of this town eventually,
はるか北の国に旅して オーロラをこの目で見る事です
Journey to the distant northern land, and watch the aurora lights there
そこにあなたがニャンニャンニャン 居てくれたらなんて素敵でしょう
If you, meow meow meow, could be there with me, it'd be wonderful
だけどそれは叶わないらしい...
But I guess it will never happen...
生き方はニャンニャンニャン
My way of living, meow meow meow
そう簡単には変えられないの
Cannot be changed so easily
それに私を飼っている 女の子を一人にできないわ
Besides, I simply do not have the heart to abandon my owner
話の途中よニャンニャンニャン
I'm still talking, meow meow meow
あらもう行っちゃうの?ねえちょっと!
Are you already leaving? Come on, wait!
明日もここに来ていいのよ 待ってるから...
Please feel free to visit me again tomorrow, I'll be waiting...
これは可愛いお嬢さん
What a cute young lady we have here!
真っ白な毛がとても素敵ね
Your pure white fur is so lovely!
こんな月が綺麗な夜は
In this night with such a beautiful moon,
私と一緒にお話しませんか
Would you like to talk together with me?
ニャン生は一度きり
A cat can only live once,
楽しが勝ちなのです
So it's all about having fun!
あなたを縛る首輪は
Shall I tear that collar around your neck
噛み千切ってあげましょう
To pieces with my teeth?
野良は最高ニャンニャンニャン
Being a stray is the best! Meow meow meow
魚くすねて、ハト追いかけて
I steal fish to eat, chase after pigeons,
昼間は働く人間を
And look down on the working humans
尻目に屋根の上で夢現
from the roof, where I doze off into a light nap
あなたも自由にニャンニャンニャン
You should be free, too. Meow meow meow
素敵な仲間も紹介しましょう
I'll also introduce some great buddies to you
さあ、その窓を開けて
Come now, open up that window,
飛び出すのです!
And leap right out!
ふぇー、ありがとー！
Phew, thank you!
というわけで、あ、素晴らしいニャン生をルイちゃんと歌いました。
And that's why, ah, we sang "Aa, Subarashiki Nyansei" with Lui-chan.
いやね、ハモリがすごく難しくって、ルイちゃんとね、最近ね、すごい練習もしたんですけど
Man, the harmonies were super difficult, and Lui-chan and I practiced really hard recently, but...
いやなんか、ね、本番でこんな感じでできると思ってなかったので
I didn't think we could pull it off like this on the actual show,
なんか、あれ?しっぽある?あれ?あれ?
And I'm like, wait, do I have a tail? Huh? Huh?
なんか、はー、ちょっと緊張がちょっとほぐれましたね。
Phew, my nervousness loosened up a bit.
でもまだまだ緊張する曲だらけなんですけども、いやねルイちゃんがすごいね、ステキな低音ボイスで
Though there are still plenty of songs that make me nervous, Lui-chan has such a lovely low voice,
まあ私ね、この曲をね、あの低音好きだからルイちゃんなんですよ。「こういうこの上と下の曲でどうですか?」って言われて
and I like the low part of this song, so that's why I asked Lui-chan. She suggested doing the upper and lower part song.
「ぜひぜひ!ぜひぜひ!」って言ってやった曲だったので
And I eagerly agreed, so it was that kind of song.
すごいなんか、一緒に歌えて嬉しかったし
It made me so happy to sing it together with her,
ね!ちゃんとここで二人でこう、おめかしをとってできたのがとっても嬉しかったです!
Right! And being able to dress up and do it together here made me so happy!
ルイちゃんほんとにありがとうー!
Lui-chan, thank you so much!
そしてそして、次の曲なんですけども、次の曲は新曲になっております。
And as for the next song, the next song is a brand new one.
ま、今日ね、受注生産で届いた人がいっぱいいると思うんですけど、えー、「Happy Meowthday!!」っていう曲です。
Well, I think many people received it today through made-to-order production, um, it's a song called "Happy Meowthday!!".
これですね、これなんですけども、あの受注終わっちゃってるんですけど
As for this, well, the orders have already closed, but
えー、今度、え、いつだっけな、もうすぐ、配信が18日から配信が決まっておりますので
um, streaming is decided to start very soon from the 18th, so
曲が気になるなとか、いいなって思った人はぜひチェックしてもらえると嬉しいです!よろしくお願いします!
if you're curious about the song or think it's nice, I'd be happy if you check it out! Thank you!
可愛い、可愛い、ふふふ
So cute, so cute, haha
それではその曲を歌っていこうと思います!聞いてください、「Happy Meowthday!!」
Well then, I'd like to sing that song! Please listen to, "Happy Meowthday!!"
もふもふ 抱きしめ にゃんにゃんにゃん
Fluffy, hold me tight, meow meow meow
そのつぶらな瞳、ずるでしょ。。
Those adorable eyes, isn't that unfair?
一年に大事な記念日もキミと一緒だよ
Even on this once-a-year special anniversary, I'm with you.
さぁ、Happy Meowthday!!
Now, Happy Meowthday!!
大変だ、大変だ、甘えん坊、始まった…!!
Oh no, oh no, the clingy mode has begun...!!
そんなの、もう反則だよ。悶絶級の事件だよ
That's already a foul play. It's an agonizing-level incident!
もしかして、今きっと、心通じ合ったの？
Could it be that our hearts just connected right now?
思わせぶりな態度に揺さぶられて
Swayed by your teasing attitude,
そんな今日は私の大切な日
this day is my precious day.
いちごのショートケーキもプレゼントも
Strawberry shortcake and presents too,
嬉しくてたまらなくて 笑顔で頬が痛くて
I'm so overjoyed that my cheeks hurt from smiling,
幸せって意外と隣にあるのかな？
could happiness be right beside me after all?
いつも通り「大好きだ」って笑いながら
Always smiling as I say 'I love you',
いつも通り 隣で寝転びたいの
I want to lie down right beside you as usual.
もふもふパーティーは始まったばかりだよ
The fluffy party has only just begun!
キミとの Happy Birthday,
Happy Birthday with you,
つまりは Happy Meowthday!!
which means, Happy Meowthday!!
もうすぐ日付も変わる頃
Just before the date changes,
猫魔法が解ける静けさの前に
before the quietness when the cat magic wears off,
思いふけってなんか妙に寂しくなって
I get lost in thought and feel strangely lonely,
ヒトの気持ちってなんだか難しいな
human feelings are kind of complicated.
いつも通り「大好きだ」って笑いながら
Always smiling as I say 'I love you',
いつも通り 隣で寝転びたいの
I want to lie down right beside you as usual.
もふもふパーティーは終わりの時間だよ
It's time for the fluffy party to end,
さよなら Happy Birthday,
so goodbye, Happy Birthday,
ありがとう Happy Meowthday!!
thank you, Happy Meowthday!!
今この瞬間が思い出になって、残っていますように。
May this very moment become a memory that stays with us.
また目を覚ました時、隣にいますように。
May you be right by my side when I open my eyes again.
もふもふ抱きしめんにゃにゃんにゃん
Hugging you tight with a Nya-Nya-Nyan,
その甘い鳴き声、ずるでしょ。
that sweet meow of yours is unfair.
さぁ、Happy Meowthday!!
Now, Happy Meowthday!!
はい、ということで Happy Meowthday でしたー！
Yes, so that was Happy Meowthday!
ありがとうございます！可愛すぎる本当に！ありがとうございます、うれし！あ、ぱちぱちもありがとうございます！
Thank you very much! It's so cute, really! Thank you, I'm so happy! Ah, thank you for the applause too!
超素晴らしい！ありがとうございます！
Super wonderful! Thank you so much!
いや、あの、なんかね、この動きが可愛くできるかなってちょっと不安だったんですけど、
Um, well, you know, I was a little worried if I could make this movement look cute,
可愛くできてよかったなって思います！みんなが可愛いと思ってくれていたらとても嬉しいです。めっちゃ可愛すぎる、ありがとう！お誕生日おめでとうありがとう！
I'm glad it turned out cute! I'd be very happy if everyone thinks it's cute. It's super cute, thank you! Happy birthday, thank you!
また飲み物を飲もう。
Let's drink some more drinks.
めっちゃかわ、ありがとうありがとう！
Super cute, thank you, thank you!
はい、ということでね、
Yes, so,
後でまたもう一曲新曲を歌おうと思っているので最後まで見てってね！
I'm planning to sing another new song later, so make sure to watch until the end!
というわけで、次のゲストさんのためにですね、ちょっと変身をしちゃおうかなって思います！
With that said, for our next guest, I think I'll transform a little bit!
行くよー！
Here we go!
なんだと思う？なんだと思う？何に変身すると思う？めっちゃ飲み物飲めてえらい。まあ、そうだね、めっちゃ飲み物は飲めてるけども、
What do you think? What do you think? What do you think I'm transforming into? I'm doing great drinking lots of drinks. Well, that's right, I'm drinking lots of drinks, but
えーじゃあドリンクタイムは終わったということで、じゃあ！
um, well, the drink time is over, so, well!
ひらけー、どーん！
Open sesame, boom!
はい、ということでまだ私服です。でも私服でさ、ここ立つのはさ、初めてなんだけど、なんかこのこの服でさ、ここなんか、
Yes, so this is still my casual clothes. But wearing casual clothes standing here is a first for me, but somehow in this outfit, standing here...
なんか、ちょっと豪華だね、なんかそんな感じがしますね。
it feels kind of luxurious, I get that feeling.
というわけで、早速この衣装でね、会いたい人と、登場と、登場と思いまーす！
With that said, in this outfit, I'd like to introduce someone I want to see, and present—wait, I mean appearance!
しろっちゃーん！
Shiro-chan!
あれ？この辺りに私服姿のアイドルがいるって聞いたんだけど、どこかな？どこかな？どこかな？
Huh? Around here, I heard there's an idol wearing casual clothes, where could she be? Where could she be? Where could she be?
あっそこにいるの！ももものふらんちゃーん！
Ah, right there! Momomo no Furan-chan!
わー！ひゃー！
Waー! Hyaー!
ちゃちゃ、さっきから見てて、今度はももいろの姿で来てくれたんですね！
Cha-cha, I've been watching since earlier, and now you came in a peach-colored outfit!
そうなのー！
That's right!
本当に、プラトンさん、そして
Truly, Platomo-san, and—
え、たけの… そらちゃん！はい！
Wait, Take no... Sora-chan! Yes!
お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
いや、もう、かなたんのその服もかわいいんだけどさ、
Kanata, that outfit of yours is so cute too, but...
もういっぱい、いっぱい、そらちゃんの活動を見てきたから、
I've watched Sora-chan's activities so much, so...
今日迎えられて本当に良かったね！
I'm so glad we could celebrate today!
うん、本当にうれしい。そしてね、かなちゃんとずっと一緒に
Yeah, I'm really happy. And, you know, I've always wanted to be with Kanata...
同じステージに立って歌いたくって、
and sing on the same stage together,
白今プロポーズされてる？
Shiro, are you being proposed to right now?
だからその夢をかなえたくて、そう呼んだんだよね。来てくれて本当にありがとう。
That's why I wanted to make that dream come true, so I called you here. Thank you so much for coming.
こちらこそだよ。白もあのそらちゃんの歌が大好きで、
It's mutual. Shiro also loves Sora-chan's songs so much,
本当に、アイドルとして憧れてるので、ずっと一緒に歌いたいって思ってたから本当にうれしい。
and truly admires her as an idol, so I've always wanted to sing together, so I'm really happy.
どうしよう
What should I do?
そらちゃん、あのせっかくなので、白ができる何かことで、あ、リクエストとかしたりしますか？
Sora-chan, since we have the chance, is there anything Shiro can do? Like, take a request?
え、私なんか、え、それなんか本当に私だけが得しちゃうんですけど
Eh, for someone like me, eh, that would really just benefit me alone, but
ぎゅっと、初めての、え、ハグ？ハグしてほしい！
A hug? I want a hug for the first time!
そらちゃん、本当によく頑張ったね。
Sora-chan, you worked really hard.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
これからもずっとずっとアイドルの姿を見せてね。
Please keep showing us your idol self forever.
もちろん！私私、ずっと先輩として、なんか、そらちゃんのことを追いかけてきてたので、今一緒に、こうやってステージに立てるのが本当に幸せです。ありがとうございます。
Of course! I've always chased after Sora-chan as a senior, so being able to stand on stage together like this now is truly happiness. Thank you.
こちらこそだよ。白も、なんかいろんな変わりゆく人とか雨の日もそらちゃんの歌を聴いたりして、勝手に応援したり、
It's mutual. Shiro has also listened to Sora-chan's songs through various changing times and rainy days, cheering on her on her own,
なんかそらちゃんは、本当にはじめは、あのバブみとかママみを感じるっていうので、
And at first, Sora-chan gave off this 'babumi' or 'mamami' vibe,
あのそらちゃんに出会った時期もあったんですけど、なんだろう、本当に一歩一歩そらちゃんの手を繋ぎながら、あいつもね、後ろからついてきたんだね。
and there was a time I met Sora-chan, but holding Sora-chan's hand step by step, Kanata also followed from behind.
自分の道を進んでいて、本当にキラキラしてて、かっこいいで、うれしい、ありがとう。
Walking your own path, truly sparkling and cool, I'm happy, thank you.
こちらこそだよ。今日もね、リハーサルでいっぱい、いっぱいそらちゃんをね、喜ばせようと思って練習して楽しんでるの？
It's mutual. Today too, practicing hard in rehearsal to make Sora-chan happy, enjoying it!
ありがとう、なんか恥ずかしいんだけど。じゃあさ、もっとちゃんと歌ったり白をアイドルの脳殺する
Thank you, it's kind of embarrassing. Then, sing properly and make Shiro's idol brain melt?
分かったよ。ちゃん練習します！あ、違う違う。もっと今日、あの他の歌も聞けたら、そういうこと？
Understood. I'll practice properly! Ah, no no. More today, if I could hear other songs too, is that it?
なんか、万歳をしたいのかな？あ、万歳しますか？どうも、どうもそらちゃんでした！
Like, do you want to do a banzai? Ah, shall we do banzai? Hello, hello, it was Sora-chan!
え、ときのそらでーす。
Eh, it's Tokino Sora.
かなちゃんは私服ですね。そうなんです。せっかくステージのね、なんかやってくれたりしないんですか？
Kanata is in casual clothes. That's right. Since it's the stage, won't you do something together?
じゃあ、やります！一緒にやります！はーい！ついに、ついに、その歌を歌いたいと思います！
Then, we'll do it! Together! Yay! Finally, we're going to sing that song!
せーの！おねがいだりーん！
Ready, go! Onegai Darling!
おねだりしてみて欲しいの ダーリン
I want you to pester me, darling.
あなたたちは私の言うこと全然聞かない
You don't listen to what I say at all.
あれほどやめてって言った煙草もお酒も
I've told you so much to stop smoking and drinking.
毎日二箱七缶一日たりとも欠かさず肝臓やられてお釈迦になっても
Every day two packs and seven cans without fail, even if your liver gets ruined
看病してあげないんだから
I won't nurse you.
ああ言えばこう言う てんででも聞かない あなたのハートは真っ黒です
You have a comeback for every remark, your heart is pitch black.
言いたいことは言わないし
You won't say what you want to say.
ねぇ、それって馬鹿みたいじゃない?
Hey, isn't that like an idiot?
そうじゃない? じゃない? じゃない?
Isn't that right? right? right?
いつも思わせぶりな感じで 察してほしい感じで
Always a tease, wanting me to guess.
わざわざ口にしないの ずるくない?
Not saying it on purpose, isn't that unfair?
お願いダーリン 見て聞いて 欲しいのは 形のないもの
Please darling, look and listen, what I want is a shapeless thing.
馬鹿にしないわ 見て聞いて 覗いてよ 瞳の奥の方
I won't make fun of you, look and listen, peek deep in my eyes.
真っ直ぐ見つめて お願いしてみて 欲しいの?
Gaze straight ahead, do you want me to pester you?
ダーリン 私はあなたの気持ちを全然知らないの
Darling, I don't know your feelings at all.
あんなに健気に見つめてきたのに 今ではすっかり知らんぷりって
Even though I gazed at you so gallantly, now you pretend not to know.
いうか それって胡坐かいてるだけなんじゃないんですかぶっちょけ
I mean, isn't that just resting on your laurels? To be frank,
舌先三寸 あなたのお陰で私のハートはボロボロです
A fast-talker, thanks to you my heart's all worn out.
つれないときはつれないし
When you're cold, you're cold.
ねぇ、なんだか馬鹿みたいじゃない?
Hey, isn't this somewhat stupid?
そうじゃない? じゃない? じゃない?
Isn't that right? right? right?
どこか足元見てる感じで 値踏みされてる感じで
Feeling you're watching your feet, feeling like I'm being appraised.
駆け引きやら勝ち負けじゃないじゃない?
Is this not tactics and victory or defeat?
寡黙なダーリン ねぇ聞いて 切なさは飾りじゃないのよ
Silent darling, hey listen, pain isn't a decoration.
よそ見しないで 逃げないで 触ってよ 心の奥の方
Don't look away, don't run away, feel deep in my heart.
一瞬のことじゃない お願いしてはくれないの?
This isn't a momentary thing, won't you pester me?
言葉に出来ない臆病さは 強さじゃないのよ
The cowardice you can't put into words isn't strength.
甘えてないで 口に出してよ
Don't be spoilt, express yourself.
お願いダーリン 見て聞いて 欲しいのは 形のないもの
Please darling, look and listen, what I want is a shapeless thing.
おねだりしてみてほしいの
I want you to try and beg me,
ダーリン あなたは私の言うこと全然聞かない
Darling, you never listen to a single thing I say.
あれほどやめてって言った煙草もお酒も
Cigarettes and alcohol I begged you to quit,
毎日二箱七缶一日たりとも欠かさず
Two packs and seven cans every single day without fail.
言葉にできない臆病さは
A cowardice that cannot be put into words,
優しさことではないのよ
Is not the same as kindness.
甘えてないで不意に抱きしめよ
Don't just act spoiled, suddenly hold me close.
ねえ ちゃんとこっち向いてったら
Hey, properly turn and face me.
お願いダーリン 見て聞いて
Please, darling, look and listen.
欲しいのは形のないもの
What I want is something without form.
バカにしないでよ 見て聞いて
Don't make a fool of me, look and listen.
覗いてよ 瞳の奥の方
Peek into the depths of my eyes.
寡黙の代わり捨てないで
Instead of silence, don't throw it away,
暴いてよ 私の素顔を
Uncover my true face.
お願いダーリン そばにいて
Please, darling, stay by my side.
変わらずに 心の奥の方
Unchanging, deep within my heart.
真っ直ぐ見つめて
Look straight at me.
おねだりしてみてほしいの
I want you to try and beg me.
お願いダーリン
Please, darling!
そらちゃん！
Sora-chan!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
頑張ったね！
You did great!
またやっちゃった！
You did it again!
お願いダーリン歌っちゃいました！
We sang "Onegai Darling"!
そうなのよ。またね、AZKiちゃんとは後でお話ししたいなと思ってるんですけど、
That's right. Also, AZKi-chan and I want to talk more later, but...
まあ次のね、ゲストの方も喋りたいということで、次のゲストを呼ぼう！
Well, we want to talk with our next guest too, so let's call our next guest!
この方です！
It's this person!
わぁー！いぇい！
Yay!
いぇい！いぇい！
Yay! Yay!
はーい！はーい！
Hi! Hi!
というわけで、わたくしが参りました！皆さんこんにちは！
And so, I have arrived! Hello everyone!
いぇい！夏色まつり！夏色まつり！
Yay! Natsuiro Matsuri! Natsuiro Matsuri!
今日も元気いっぱいです！
Today I'm full of energy too!
わざわざ来てくれてありがとう！
Thanks for coming all this way!
いや全然全然全然、遠くから遥々やってきました！遠くからさ、そうだよね？そうだよ！
Not at all, I came all the way from afar! From far away, right? That's right!
遠くから遥々ありがとうございます！いやいや娘のためですから、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Thank you so much! Well, it's for my daughter's sake, happy birthday!
お母さん！お母さんじゃん！何よ！ママよあなたの子の、ママ！
Mom! You're the mom! What? I'm your child's mom!
みんな可愛いでしょう、うちの娘！見てこの顔面！今日のメイクもばっちりなんです！
Isn't she cute, my daughter? Look at this face! Today's makeup is totally on point!
メイクばっちりなんだけど。さすが私が生んだ子だね、ママ！
Makeup is on point. As expected of the child I gave birth to, Mom!
何？実はさ、今日さ大事なお披露目があって、それをね、まつりちゃんに見届けほしくって。
What? Actually, today I have an important reveal, and I wanted Matsuri-chan to witness it.
わかった！あ、それで呼んだのね！オッケーオッケーオッケー。なんで呼んだのかと思った。オッケー！見届けましょう！
I see! Oh, so that's why you called me! Okay, okay. I wondered why you called me. Okay! Let's witness it!
というわけでね、早速ね、一緒に、じゃじゃーん！
And so, right away, together, ta-da!
おお！なんだって？なんだって？なんだって？
Oh! What is it? What is it? What is it?
じゃーん！可愛い！
Ta-da! So cute!
なんて可愛いんだうちの娘！みんなスクショタイムだよ！可愛い！
How cute is my daughter! Everyone, it's screenshot time! So cute!
あらやだ可愛らしい！ありがとうございます！
Oh dear, how lovely! Thank you very much!
ただね、これはですね、まあパターン1と言いますか、まだね、全部ではないんです。ちょっとね、あの普通のスカートバージョンのほうの、新衣装ということになっております。
However, this is, well, you could say pattern 1, it's not all of it yet. It's the new costume with the regular skirt version.
え、そうなんだ！そうなんです！
Eh, is that so? That's right!
かわいいね！かわいいでしょ。なんか真っ白で、ほんと素敵じゃん。
So cute! Isn't it cute? It's pure white and really wonderful.
一番最初にまつれちに見せたくてさ。あっ、なるほどね！みんな聞いた？私が生番一番初めに見ちゃった！やったー！
I wanted to show Matsurechi first. Ah, I see! Everyone heard? I got to see it first! Yay!
えじゃあ、そんなそらちゃんのせっかくだからさ、みんなもっと近くで見たいよね？ねえ！もっと近くで見たい？本当に？
Well then, since it's Sora-chan's special occasion, everyone wants to see it closer, right? Right? You want to see it closer? Really?
ちょっとカメラマンさん、カメラ変わってもらっていいですか？
Camera person, could you please change the camera?
まつれち、ちょっと私が、今年カメラするわ。みんなうち消えるけど、まあいいよね、映らなくても。いやいやちょっと失礼じゃん！
Matsurechi, I'll operate the camera this time. Everyone will disappear, but it's fine even if we don't show, right? No no, that's a bit rude!
あーかわいい！見て！なんかセクシーね、とっても。
Ah, cute! Look! It's kind of sexy, very much so.
あらかわいい！じゃあローアングルでもよろしくて？いやローアングル全然よろしくないですよ！あ、好き、こっち見て。
Oh cute! Then how about a low angle? No, a low angle is definitely not okay! Ah, I like it, look this way.
全部出す！あ、かわいいポーズください！なんか、だっちゅーの、みたいな。
Show everything! Ah, give me a cute pose! Like, "dacchoo-no" or something.
あ、だっちゅーの？だっちゅーのわかんない！やばい世代を感じる。
Ah, dacchoo-no? I don't know dacchoo-no! Oh no, I feel my age.
じゃあなんかハート作ってみて！あら、かわいい！
Try making a heart! Ara, so cute!
ちょっと上からのアングルも失礼しちゃって。やだ、かわいい！
Excuse me for taking an angle from above too. Oh dear, so cute!
ちょっと腰にこう手を当ててこんな感じで。かわいいんだけど見てみんな、ためっちゃかわいい！
Put your hand on your waist like this. It's cute, but look everyone, so cute!
かわいいんだけど！めっっちゃかわいい！かわいいよめっっちゃ！
It's so cute! Super cute! So very cute!
え、髪もさ、実はちょっとさ、何て言うの、編み込み？編み込みみたいになってて。
Um, my hair too, actually it's like, what is it called, braided? Like braided hair.
皆さんちょっとね気合入れて髪型もね
Everyone, I put extra effort into my hair today.
ちょっと後ろも失礼しちゃっていい？
Is it okay if I show the back too?
どうぞどうぞ。
Go right ahead.
やだ素敵、見てみんな、可愛い、うちの子！
Oh, how lovely! Look everyone, so cute, my girl!
ママ、こっち見て、ママの方見て！
Mama, look over here, look at Mama!
ああ可愛い、見て、可愛いみんな、
Aww, so cute, look, everyone's so cute,
みんなの方手振ってるよ、ほら！可愛い！
Waving at you all, see? So cute!
すごい可愛い、あ、いいですね。
Super cute, ah, nice.
可愛い！
Cute!
あ、ありがとうございます、カメラさん。
Ah, thank you, cameraman.
すみませんカメラおばちゃって。
Sorry, camera lady.
めちゃめちゃ可愛いカットね。
Such a super cute shot.
めちゃくちゃのりノリで撮影してくれるじゃん。
You're filming us with such great enthusiasm.
いや可愛いなと思って。
Yeah, I thought it was so cute.
ありがとう！ありがとうございます。
Thank you! Thank you very much.
すみませんカメラさん。
Sorry, cameraman.
みんなスクショたくさん撮ってくれたかな？
I wonder if everyone took lots of screenshots?
撮った？みんなスクショ撮り忘れてない？
Did you? Everyone didn't forget to take screenshots, right?
めっちゃ可愛かったんだから。
Because she was super cute.
うちの娘可愛いって書かれて、あ、うちの娘？
People wrote "our daughter is cute"—wait, "our daughter"?
みんなの娘になったもしやて。
Could it be she became everyone's daughter?
ママがハイテンションになっちゃった。
Mama got super high-strung.
うちらの娘、ちょっと可愛いよね、今日。
Our daughter is so cute today, right?
やった！なんかこうやってね、みんなにこう見てもらえて、私も満足しちゃったな。
Yay! Seeing everyone look at her like this, I'm already satisfied.
本当に！満足しちゃった。
Really! I'm so satisfied.
じゃあ帰ろう。お疲れ様！
Well then, let's go home. Good job!
なんかおかしそうにして！なんだよ！
What's with that funny look! What?!
一緒に歌ってよ！
Sing together with us!
歌いたいの？
You wanna sing?
何よ！歌いたいよ！初めからそう言いなさいよ！
What?! I want to! Then say so from the start!
そう言います、や。
I'll say it, yeah.
いや、めっちゃ緊張するんだけど。
Man, I'm super nervous though.
ちょっと気裏腹したしちゃってもいい？
Is it okay if my true feelings slip out?
今から歌う曲、ちょっと、踊りがあるんですよ。
The song we're singing from now on has some choreography.
あのね、ずっと横でこうやって練習してんの。
You see, she was practicing right next to me like this.
もう必死なんだ！
She was so desperate!
全然ずっとこうやって、ずっとこうやって、ずっとこうやってんの！
She kept doing this the whole time!
琴乃ネッチに教えてもらったんだって。
Kotono-necchi taught her, apparently.
そうだから、なんか、目で上げて、頑張っている、あの娘をうちらで見よ。
So, like, let's watch her trying her best with our own eyes.
絶対間違える、結構可愛い。
She'll definitely make mistakes, which is pretty cute.
いや、大丈夫だって！参戦目の気持ちで打ち切れてるからさ、すごい関西弁になっちゃったわ！
No, it's fine! I'm coming in with the feeling of a third-timer, so my Kansai dialect came out strong!
そう、参戦目の気持ちで来てるから、だからみんなもその気持ちで見でんねん。
Yeah, I'm coming with that feeling, so you guys watch with that feeling too.
もう私たまにチラチラ見ちゃうわ。
I'll be peeking at her occasionally.
いいよ、全然見て。見ていいから、ちょっとみんなパパとママにしてあげてや。
It's fine, go ahead. Look all you want, and be her papa and mama.
もう、大丈夫だって。心配性やねん、めっちゃ。
Hey, it's fine. You're worrying too much.
ねえ、でも緊張してるけど、みんなに、まあ歌えば大丈夫だと思うんだけど、まあダンスがぐちゃぐちゃになったらどうしよう。
Yeah, but even though I'm nervous, singing for everyone should be fine, but what if the dance gets all messy?
でもうちも忘れるとこあるし、たぶん。
Well, I might forget parts too, probably.
あ、本当？
Oh really?
あ、大丈夫、大丈夫。可愛いければよししてくれてるから。
Ah, it's fine, it's fine. As long as she's cute, they'll forgive it.
でもダメやなって思ったら、こうやってやったときは大丈夫や。
But if you think "this is bad," doing this means it's okay.
頑張り、頑張ります。
I'll do my best.
頑張る？がんばれ、がんばれって、みんな応援してあげてな。
Do your best? Everyone, cheer her on with "do your best!"
はーい！
Okay!
はい！
Yes!
じゃ、一緒にいようね。せーの、ハッピーシンセサイザー！
Well then, let's do it together. Ready, set, Happy Synthesizer!
ハッピーシンセサイザ 君の胸の奥まで
Happy Synthesizer, deep into your heart,
届くようなメロディ 奏でるよ
I'll play a melody that reaches you.
僅か散った淡い片思い
Fading fragments of a fleeting crush,
笑い話だね 今となれば
It's just a funny story looking back now.
見る物全て 輝いて見えた
Everything I looked at seemed to shine bright,
あの日々がキレイに 笑ってるよ
Those days are smiling back at us so purely.
我慢する事だけ 覚えなきゃいけないの?
Do I only have to learn how to hold back?
「大人になって頂戴ね」にならなくていいよ
You don't need to become an adult like that.
知らない事ばかり 知らないなんて言えなくて
There's so much I don't know, but I can't admit it,
「大変お似合いで」ウソついてゴメンね
"You two make a lovely pair," sorry for lying.
ハッピーシンセサイザ 君の胸の奥まで
Happy Synthesizer, deep into your heart,
届くようなメロディ 奏でるよ
I'll play a melody that reaches you.
つまらない「たてまえ」や ヤな事全部
All those boring facades and unpleasant things,
消してあげるから この音で
I'll erase them all with this sound.
何の取り柄もない 僕に唯一少しだけど
For someone with no special traits like me,
出来る事 心躍らせる 飾らない言葉
There's one small thing I can do: unpretentious words
電子音で伝えるよ 好きになる事
Conveyed through electronic sounds, falling in love
理屈なんじゃなくて 「こじつけ」なんじゃない?
Isn't it less about logic and more about excuses?
時代のせいと 諦めたらそこまで
If you give up and blame the times, that's the end of it.
踏み出さなくちゃ何も始まらない
Nothing starts unless you take a step forward.
「ごめんね夜遅く 寝るところだったでしょ?」
"Sorry for calling late at night, were you going to bed?"
「驚いた私もかけようとしていた」
"I was surprised, I was just about to call you too."
心の裏側をくすぐられているような
Like having the back of our hearts tickled,
惹かれ合う2人に 幸せな音を
A happy sound for two people drawn to each other.
ハッピーシンセサイザ ほらね楽しくなるよ
Happy Synthesizer, see? It gets so fun,
涙拭うメロディ 奏でるよ
I'll play a melody to wipe away tears.
強がらなくたっていいんじゃない? 別に
You don't have to act so tough all the time, do you?
自分に素直になればいい
It's fine to just be honest with yourself.
何の取り柄もない 僕に唯一少しだけど
For someone with no special traits like me,
出来る事 涙拭うメロディ 奏でるよ
There's one small thing I can do: play a melody to wipe away tears.
強がらなくたっていいんじゃない? 別に
You don't have to act so tough all the time, do you?
自分に素直になればいい ちょっと照れるような
It's fine to be honest with yourself, with a slightly shy,
単純な気持ち 電子音で伝えるよ
Simple feeling conveyed through electronic sounds.
ハッピーシンセサイザ
Happy Synthesizer
君の胸の奥まで届くようなメロディ奏でるよ
playing a melody that reaches deep into your heart.
僅か散った淡い片想い 笑い話だね今となれば
It's all a funny story now, looking back at that fragile crush.
見る物全て輝いて見えた あの日々がキレイに笑ってるよ
Everything looked so glamorous back then, and those days are smiling at us.
我慢する事だけ覚えなきゃいけないの?
Do we only learn to hold back our feelings?
「大人になって頂戴ね?」ならなくていいよ
"Just act like an adult," we don't really have to.
ハッピーシンセサイザ ほらね楽しくなるよ
Happy Synthesizer, see how everything's fun?
涙拭うメロディ奏でるよ
Playing a melody to wipe away tears.
強がらなくたっていいんじゃない? 別に自分に素直になれればいい
Don't pretend to be stronger than you are, just be true to yourself.
何の取り柄もない 僕に唯一つ 少しだけど出来る事
Although I have no other talents, this is the one thing I can do.
ちょっと照れるような 単純な気持ち 電子音で伝えるよ
With simple feelings and electric sounds, I'll pass it on to you.
あー！かわいい！
Ah, how cute!
緊張した？
You're nervous?
なにそれ？
What is that?
そうなんです！
That's right!
めっちゃかわいい！
It's super cute.
え、いろいろあるパターンの、2パターン目！
And there are various patterns. This is the second pattern!
かわいい！
Cute!
あります！
There is!
みてみて、このドレス！
Look at this dress!
可愛すぎる！
It's too cute!
かわいい！ありがと！
Cute! Thank you!
あ、おおって、ありがとうございます！
Oh, thank you very much!
めっちゃかわいい！みてみて、すごくない？
It's super cute! Look at it, isn't it amazing?
お姫様みたいや！
Like a princess!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
かわいい！
Cute!
じゃあこれでツーショット撮ってもらおうか。
Should we take a photo of this?
ツーショットいいよ？
A two-shot is good!
いぇーい！
Yay!
かわいい！
So cute!
めっちゃかわいいねんけど！
It's super cute, though!
ねえ、ありがとう。
Thank you.
私もね、これね、最初見たときに
I also... When I first saw this...
え、こんなに可愛いのか私が着ていいのかなって思った。
"Is this cute thing really something I can wear?" I thought.
あー、可愛すぎる！
Ah, it's too cute!
ねえ、シロちゃんもまだ見てくれてるかな？
Hey, Shiro-chan, are you still watching?
シロちゃん！いろはから、シロちゃーん！
Shiro-chan, from Sora... Shiro-chan!
シロちゃーん！シロちゃーん！
Shiro-chan! Shiro-chan!
呂律が回らんかった！
Tongue tied!
あ、シロちゃん！大丈夫か？おかえり！
Oh! Shiro-chan? Are you okay?
おかえり！戻ったよ！
Welcome back!
かわいい！ありがとう！
Thank you!
まず娘さんは、はいはい。結婚でもされるんでしょうか？
First of all, is Ms. Daughter getting married?
その美しい姿で！
What a gorgeous appearance!
いや、もううちの子は誰にも渡したくない！
No, our child... I don't want to give her to anyone.
テレビの厄介な親だ。テレビの厄介な、もうお母さんもきれいでしよね？
TV's annoying parent, right? TV's annoying...
あ、そう！嬉しいわ！
Oh, really? I'm so happy!
すごくきれいきれいだったよ。
It's super pretty!
ちょっと500歳のママ、まだまだ頑張ります！
I'm still 500 years old, so I'll keep doing my best.
元気いっぱいの新人VTuberってよく間違えられましたけど。
"I'm a Genki VTuber" is often mistaken.
なんで、なんで、なんでだ？
Why? Why? Why?
わかんない、どうしてなんだろうね。
I don't know why, though.
新人、でもね、モンスターペアレントは阻止したんで。
Shinzin, but I fostered a monster parent, so...
まだ大丈夫。あなた清らかなペアレントでよろしいか。
You're a pure-hearted parent, right?
ありがとう清らかペアレント。清らかペアレントです！
Thank you, pure parent!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
二人とも本当に！
We both... truly...
もうなんか心は浄化されるし、めっちゃダンス練習したの、本当によし！
My heart is purified, and we practiced dancing so hard!
本当によし！
Really!
かわいかった、めっちゃ！
It was so cute!
よっちゅゆーち！
Yocchiyu-chi!
もう必死だったよ。踊れた？
We were desperate. Did you dance?
たぶん隠れてたよ。
Probably... were you hiding?
みんな上手だったよね？
Everyone was doing great, right?
みんな上手だった人、パチパチパチパチ！
Everyone who did well, let's high-five!
もうたまに誤魔化してたけど。
Well, sometimes I was just covering.
上手だったよ、めちゃめちゃ！
You did great, really!
本当に！そらちゃん、楽しかった！
Really! Sora-chan, it was so fun.
お衣装で、歌をね、ショートバージョンでも歌っていましたが！
With this outfit, we sang songs, and we even sang in short versions, but...
すきのポイントはどこですか？
What is your favorite point?
ショートの、これ、こっち？こっちの衣装？
Short, this, this? This outfit's...
ああ、やっぱりこれね、座るとわかるんだけど、すごい！
Ah, I see. This, when you sit down, you understand, but...
わあ！ふわふわ感じ！
Look at that! Fluffy!
ここの中の、このお化粧の上のステージで、
Here, like, on this Okeshi stage...
白鳥みたいだ！白鳥みたい！
Like Hachiko! Hachiko!
このね、なんかヒラヒラがいっぱいあって、こうボリュームがいっぱいあって、なんか
This, like, lots of ruffles, lots of volume, and...
こう、なんて言うんだろう、白って地味な色だとは思うんだけど、
What should I call it? White is a plain color, I think, but...
本当だよね。でもそれがなんかこの衣装の形で映えるみたいな。
That's true. But it stands out in this outfit's shape!
確かに！
Indeed!
かわいい！
Cute!
え、私さ、やっぱりさ、シロちゃんもさ、
And me, you know, Shiro-chan too...
いよっ。うん、そう。
Yes! So...
新しい衣装じゃん！
A new outfit, right?
なんかね、かわいいよね！
Cute, right?
なんて足を、素敵な御御足が
Look at those legs! Such wonderful legs!
出ておられること！
Being shown like that!
いや、素敵な親御さんちょっとおかしい気がしますよ。
Well, the mom's outfit looks a bit weird.
なんで？なんで？
Why? Why?
なんかハーハーしてます。
I'm just sniffing.
ローアングルで行きませんか？
Let's go with the low angle, shall we?
あ、あの、そらちゃんが今日主役なんで、
Sora-chan is the main character today.
二人とも主役だったら、二人ともローアングル、あー素敵！
If the two of us are the main characters, then our low-angle...
あー素敵！
Ah, wonderful!
あー素敵だこと。ちょっと私も混ぜさせて戴いて、
Ah, wonderful! Let me join in on that too.
ローアングル！
Low angle!
これだぞ！
This is it!
私もアイドルだったわね
I'm an idol too, aren't I?
そうだよ！みんなアイドルだよ！
That's right! Everyone's an idol!
あら可愛い
My, how cute.
そうあら可愛い、私たち
Yes, how cute we are.
可愛いわ。みんな見て、
We're cute, right? Everyone look,
可愛いでしょう？
aren't we cute?
みんなもマジる？ みんなもマジる？
Do you all join in too? Do you all join in?
みんなもこうね、麗圧ある感じで
You guys also have that sort of majestic aura...
麗圧？
Majestic aura?
怖いな、麗圧は。
That's terrifying.
可愛い麗圧です。
It's a cute majestic aura.
素敵ね。
Wonderful.
でもこの3人もう、えっと、ずっとVtuberとして活動してきている3人だから
But since these three have been active as VTubers for so long...
だからね、なんかふたりとも来てくれるって奇跡だなと思ってて
So I think it's a miracle that both of them came.
そうかな？奇跡こそだよ！
Is that so? It's nothing short of a miracle!
だってもう、頑張り続けてきた子がご褒美に、
Because the kids who kept working hard are getting rewarded,
もう、みんなも喜んでくれる
and everyone is happy for them.
すごい、なんかもっと
That's amazing, like...
もう私がこんなに甘やかされていいのかなって ちょっと不安になっちゃう
I wonder if it's okay for me to be pampered this much, I get a bit nervous.
甘やかしたいからさ、囚人と宇宙人にしよう。おてて…
Since I want to pamper you, let's make you a prisoner and an alien. Hold hands...
なになれ？じゃあ、囚人。囚われのそらちゃん
What should we be? Then, a prisoner. Sora-chan, the captive prisoner.
どういうこと？囚われました！囚われたそら！囚われてる！
What do you mean? I was captured! Captive Sora! Being captured!
そらちゃん、甘やかそ。そらちゃんのいいところは、うん、顔面、見た目、性格、声、ボディ、正解！
Sora-chan, let's pamper you. The good things about Sora-chan are her face, appearance, personality, voice, body, correct!
えい！
Yay!
めっちゃ褒めちぎってくれるじゃん
You're praising me so much.
え、本当にこんななってね、歌も歌ってこれて、こん、たくさんおしゃべりもしてくれて、
Um, truly being like this, being able to sing songs, talking so much,
もう私すごい幸せ者だなって思ってる
I really feel like I'm a fortunate person.
よかった！本当に
I'm glad! Truly.
そしてね、なんかしあわせなの。みんなもすごい喜んでくれてて
And you know, I feel so happy. Everyone is so happy for me.
そうだよ！みんなの力でそらここまで来れました。ありがとうございます！
That's right! With everyone's support, Sora made it this far. Thank you very much!
みんなのおかげです。ありがとうございます。
Thanks to everyone. Thank you very much.
これからも毎秒慈しみながら育ててあげてください。可愛い可愛いくしてあげてください。ママからのお願いです。
Please continue to cherish and raise her every second. Make her super cute. That's a request from mama.
ふたりの、ふたりのところもぜひ遊びに行かせてね！
Please let us go visit both of your places too!
優しさだ！私もふたりのところに遊びに行かせてね！
That's kindness! Please let me go visit your places too!
わかった！いつでも！クレーンの遊びに来るの待ってるよ！
Understood! Anytime! I'm waiting for you to come play at the crane!
私を遊びに行かせてねが言えても私は大満足です。あ本当ですか？
Even if I get to say "let me go visit," I'm fully satisfied. Oh really?
そらちゃんはこの後もね、アイドルでそう思うのでえいを送ります！
Sora-chan, since you'll continue being an idol after this, I'll send you an "ei"!
頑張ってそらちゃん！ありがとう！
Do your best, Sora-chan! Thank you!
ね、せっかく来てくれたからさ、ふたりはさ、みんなに言いたいこととか、告知とかあったらいっちゃいなよ。
Hey, since you came all this way, if you guys have anything you want to say to everyone, or any announcements, go ahead and say it.
私は告知は特にないので、あの、まあ適度にTwitterでも見てください。ときのそらをよろしくお願いします。
I don't really have any announcements, so uh, just check Twitter occasionally. Please treat Tokino Sora well.
お母さん！特にないからね！大決定しましょう。
Mother! Because there's nothing special! Let's make a big decision.
じゃ、タイマン、てかタイマンに、タイマンにね、あげるあげる。天神ことねをよろしくお願いします。
Then, one-on-one, I mean, let's give it to a one-on-one. Please treat Tenjin Kotone well.
白上はね、アイドルを目指してそらちゃんのように頑張っていくので、YouTubeや配信もよろしくお願いします。
Shirakami is aiming to be an idol and work hard like Sora-chan, so please support YouTube and streams as well.
ね、めんげねえんだよね。めんげってあったかいんだね。
Hey, it's so touching. Warmth is nice.
そらちゃん、いろんなシングル聴いてるよ。ありがとう！
Sora-chan, I listen to all sorts of singles. Thank you!
テンション高えなうちら！高いね！テンション高い方が楽しいじゃん！そうだね。
Our tension is so high! It is! Higher tension is more fun, right? That's right.
この後もVvがんばってね！Vvがんばるよ！あ！いってらっしゃい！ありがとうございます！
Do your best with Vv after this too! I'll do my best with Vv! Ah! Have a safe trip! Thank you!
それでは私たちは消えますか。消える？消える？置いといて置いて置いて！
Then will we disappear? Disappear? Disappear? Leave us here, leave us here!
今日のゲスト、白上フブキちゃんと天神ことねちゃんでーす！バイバーイ！
Today's guests are Shirakami Fubuki-chan and Tenjin Kotone-chan! Bye-bye!
そらちゃんがんばって！バイバーイ！
Do your best, Sora-chan! Bye-bye!
そして私も一緒に飲み物を飲みに行ってきます。
And I'll go get a drink together too.
はい、というわけで、いやもうたくさんのゲストのみんなが来てくれて、本当にね、たくさんおしゃべりもできて、とっても幸せな空間で、みんなもね、パチパチパチパチと温かいコメントありがとうございます。
Yes, and so, many guests came, we got to chat so much, it's such a happy space, and thank you everyone for the warm clapping and comments.
え、本当に私はいろんな人に恵まれてるなと思っておりますので、これからもね、ま後半あるので、後半戦いっぱいいこうと思います。
Um, I really feel blessed to be surrounded by many people, so since there's a second half coming up, I'm going to go all out for the second half.
さて、ということでね、次のゲストの人と一緒に歌っていきたいと思います。
Now, with that said, I'd like to sing together with the next guest.
いきます。アイリスちゃんとヒバナ！
Here we go. IRyS-chan and "Hibana"!
コンコン優しくノックして 乗り込め心の脱獄船
Knock gently, con-con, and board the prison ship of the heart
妄想ばかりがフラッシュして 加速するパルス答えはどこだろな
Only delusions flash, accelerating the pulse, where is the answer?
ざんざん弱音はミュートして くだらないことで躊躇して 冗談ばかりね あははは
Mute the endless complaints, hesitate over foolish things, it's all jokes, ahahaha
壊せない壁がキスを迫るでしょ
An unbreakable wall demands a kiss, right?
コンコン 優しくノックして
Knock knock, gently knocking,
乗り込め ココロの奪還戦
breaking into your heart's territory.
妄想ばかりが加速するパルス
My delusions pulse faster and faster,
答えはどこだろう
I wonder where the answer is.
Knock knock! let me go in and get the ace
you'll paint your face with tears that don't feel the same
now heart reinforce's up to end this game
Now heart reinforce is up to end this game,
you'd better give up and throw your mp5 away
nanana 「未完成」だって何度でも言うんだ
Nanana, saying "it's incomplete" over and over,
nanana NOを空振った愛の中で
Nanana, within a love that swung and missed at "NO".
のまれてった愛の中で
Swallowed up inside this love...
トントン これで御相殺って
Knock knock, calling it even with this,
埋まらない時にこもっちゃって
Hiding away when the void can't be filled,
完全主義はスモーキーに
Making perfectionism smoky,
孤高する声に目眩とモノトーン
Dizziness and monotone in a solitary voice.
i hate it, taking both will fix it
i hate it, break us both and mix it
yeah, just rip out my heart while you're at it
i just can't love a love so underwhelming,
吐息、厭 どっちも選んで
Sighs and disgust, choosing both,
吐息、厭 どっちも壊して
Sighs and disgust, destroying both,
心の根をひき抜いて
Pulling out the roots of my heart.
make it hurt inside a little more
it's much more fun to hide it while we're laughing,
make it melt so i can know for sure
"it's incomplete," and time again i'll tell you
nanana 「未完成」だって何度でも言うんだ
Nanana, saying "it's incomplete" over and over,
nanana NOを空振った愛の中で のまれてった愛の中で
Nanana, within a love that swung and missed at "NO".
いりすちゃん、ありがとう！
IRyS-chan, thank you so much!
祝ってくれてとっても嬉しい！
I'm so happy you celebrated with me!
映像で歌って最高！
Singing together on screen is amazing!
そんなわけないや
There's no way that's true.
わかってくれるでしょ
You'll understand, won't you?
その頭を打ち抜いて
Shoot right through that head of yours.
打ち抜いて
Shoot right through it.
終わんない愛を抱いてたくないの
I don't want to embrace an endless love,
もっとちゃんと不安にしてよ
Make me feel properly anxious instead.
いないいないばれで演じて欲しいの
Play peek-a-boo and act it out for me,
もっとちゃんと応えてよ
And respond to me properly.
nanana 「未完成」だって何度でも言うんだ
Nanana, saying "it's incomplete" over and over,
nanana NOを空振った愛の中で
Nanana, within a love that swung and missed at "NO".
のまれてった愛の中で
Swallowed up inside this love...
深いない愛を愛したくないの
I don't want to love a deep, heavy love,
もっとちゃんと痛くしてよ
Make it hurt inside a little more.
笑えないくらいがきっと楽しいの
It's much more fun when we can't even laugh,
もっとちゃんと溶かしてよ
Melt me down properly.
nanana 「未完成」だって何度でも言うんだ
Nanana, saying "it's incomplete" over and over,
nanana NOを空振った愛の中で
Nanana, within a love that swung and missed at "NO".
のまれてった愛の中で
Swallowed up inside this love...
あずきちゃんと、刹那ティックコード！
With Azki-chan... Setsunatic Code!
あずきちゃんお誕生日おめでとう！
Azki-chan, happy birthday!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
歌うぞー！いくぞー！
Let's sing! Let's go!
いつだって未来のためばかり
Always living only for the sake of the future,
今という時間を費やすけれど
Spending away the time we call "now".
今だけは 今だけの感傷破ることができたら
If only we could break through this fleeting moment's sentiment,
OFFにして断ち切ったココロがもう一度動き出すよ
The heart we switched off and cut off will start moving once again.
震え出しそうな胸の痛みも涙の理由もすべて強さに変えて
Turning every trembling pain in our chest and reason for tears into strength,
飲み込んだ想い仰いだ空に飛ばす
Letting the swallowed feelings fly up into the sky we look up at,
繋がるメロディー流れる星に変わっていく
Transforming into connected melodies and flowing stars.
キミのために歌うよ キミに届くようにと
Singing for you, so that it reaches you,
輝きは世界軸を超えてく
Its brilliance transcends world axes.
確かにここで重ね合えたコード
The chords we surely overlapped right here,
ふれ合う音が光になって降り注ぐ
The touching sounds turn into light pouring down.
この瞬間が永遠にと煌めいては色づいていく キミと描いたセカイ
Sparkling as if this moment is eternity, coloring the world we painted together.
いつだって朝は来るだなんて 来てほしくない朝もあるけど
They say morning always comes, though there are mornings we wish wouldn't come.
夜の闇息潜めこのまま隠れられなくて 静寂を断ち切って叫たい声を歌に替えて
Hiding in the darkness of night, unable to stay hidden, turning the voice crying out, cutting through the silence, into song.
いつもそこにある隔て阻む壁も壊して進め
Breaking through the walls that always stand and block our way, let's push forward.
胸の奥にある忘れたふりで誤魔化し切れない傷も乗り越えていく
Overcoming even the wounds deep in our hearts we couldn't gloss over by pretending to forget.
絡まった想い音に変えて飛ばす
Turning entangled feelings into sound and setting them free,
生まれるメロディー激しく鼓動奏で合う
Generating melodies whose heartbeats intensely harmonize.
言葉だけじゃ足りない 歌いなくちゃ届かない
Words alone aren't enough; if we don't sing, it won't reach.
情熱が胸を熱くさせてく
Passion sets our hearts ablaze.
確かにここで分かり合えたコード 時間の流も逆らうように拓かれる
The chords we surely understood each other with here, carved out as if defying the flow of time.
いつだって未来のためばかり 今という時間を費やすけれど
Always focusing only on the future, spending time on the present, but...
今だけは今だけを感じ合うことができたら
if we could only feel this moment right now together,
OFFにして断ち切ったココロがもう一度動き出すよ
the heart that we switched off and cut off will start moving once again.
震え出しそうな胸の痛みも涙の理由もすべて
The trembling pain in my chest, the reason for my tears, I'll turn them all
強さに変えて
into strength.
飲み込んだ想い仰いで空に飛ばせ
Swallowed feelings, looking up, let them fly into the sky.
繋がるメロディー流れる星に変わっていく
A connecting melody turns into a flowing star.
キミのために歌うよ キミに届くようにと
I'll sing for you, so that it reaches you.
輝きは世界軸を超えていく
The radiance goes beyond the world axis.
確かにココで重ね合えた和音（コード）
The harmony we surely overlapped here,
触れ合う音が光になって降り注ぐ
the touching sounds turn into light and pour down.
この一瞬が永遠だと煌めいては色づいていく
This single moment sparkles as eternity and colors up.
キミと描いた空間（セカイ）
The space I drew with you.
いつだって朝は来るようなんて来てほしくない朝もあるけど
Morning always comes, they say—though there are mornings I don't want to come,
夜の闇息潜めこのまま隠れられなくて
hiding in the darkness of night, unable to stay hidden,
静寂を断ち切って叫びたい声を歌に変えた
I turned the voice I wanted to shout, cutting through the silence, into a song.
いつもそこにある隔て阻む壁も壊して進め
Breaking down the walls that always block the way, let's move forward.
胸の奥にある忘れたふりで誤魔化し切れない傷も乗り越えていく
Overcoming the wounds in the depths of our hearts that we pretend to forget.
絡まった想い音に変えて飛ばせ
Entangled feelings, turn them into sound and let them fly.
生まれるメロディー激しく鼓動奏で合う
The born melody plays together with a fierce heartbeat.
言葉だけじゃ足りない歌じゃなくちゃ届かない
Words alone aren't enough, it has to be a song to reach.
情熱が胸を熱くさせていく
Passion makes my chest burn hot.
確かにココで分かり合えたpassword（コード）
The password we surely understood each other with here,
時の流れも逆らうように拓かれる
opening up as if defying the flow of time.
何度だって歌うからキミの場所がいつも光に包み込まれるように
No matter how many times I'll sing, so that your place is always embraced in light.
すべてが崩れ出しそうでどこにも踏み出しえないときは送り続けるこの音楽（コード）聴こえる場所探し踏み出すよ
When everything seems to crumble, I'll keep sending this music—find a place to hear it and step out.
遠くの星が囁くように光る
Distant stars shine as if whispering.
いつも何かを伝えるように歌っている
Always singing as if to convey something.
飲み込んだ想い仰いで空に飛ばせ
Swallowed feelings, looking up, let them fly into the sky.
繋がるメロディー流れる星に変わっていく
A connecting melody turns into a flowing star.
キミのために歌うよ キミに届くようにと
I'll sing for you, so that it reaches you.
いえーい！ありがとうございます！
Yay! Thank you very much!
すらちゃん、とろちゃん！そして、そしてこの新衣装！
Sura-chan, Toro-chan! And, and this new outfit!
ね、あのリハーサルの時からこうずっと「あ、可愛い、可愛い」って言ってた、実際言ってたね！
You know, ever since rehearsal, we kept saying "Ah, it's so cute!" We really said that!
で、そんな、今日はね、なんて、新衣装のすらちゃんと、そして記念すべき今日をお祝いすることができて、めちゃくちゃ嬉しいです！
And today, I'm so super happy to celebrate Sura-chan in her new outfit and this memorable day!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
イェーイ！
Yay!
すらずーーんでした！ いや、ここでは、やっぱり、歌の3人でしゃべりますか？
Sura-z---n! Wait, should the three of us who sang talk here?
アイリスちゃん！アイリスちゃん！
IRIS-chan! IRIS-chan!
アイリスちゃん、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
IRIS-chan, happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
いや、さっきのひばなもめっちゃよかった！
Man, that "Hibana" earlier was also so good!
私ここにいていいのかな？こんな清楚で素敵なアイリスちゃんと一緒に
Is it okay for me to be here? With such a pure, wonderful IRIS-chan,
こんながくぶちが一緒に… こんなここにいていいのかな？いいのかな？
with such a picture frame... Is it really okay for me to be here? Is it?
いいんだよ！いいんだよ！可愛いよ！
It's fine! It's fine! You're cute!
いや、もうめっちゃよかったひばな！ いや、かっこよくてさ、ふたりとも…
Man, "Hibana" was super good! Man, it was cool, both of you...
もう、神、あ、神、神、え、みんな、みんな神だ、みんな神
You guys are gods, ah, gods, gods, eh, everyone, everyone is a god, everyone is a god.
みんな神だよ！
Everyone is a god!
みんな神、今日、本当の神もいましたけどね？
Everyone is a god. Today, there was an actual god too, right?
リアル神がいた、リアル神。100歳の神もいましたね。いましたね。
A real god was there, a real god. There was even a 100-year-old god. There was.
確かに。そうなんだよね、今日、ここは、ここはね、こう、なんか、みんなで楽しく、でもかっこよくみんなの
True. That's right, today, here, we thought everyone could have fun, but also look cool,
いいところがいっぱい出るようにと思って、歌を歌いたいのを…
hoping that everyone's good points would shine through, so we wanted to sing—
いや、本当に今日はそらちゃんの好きがね、たくさん詰まったセットリストだったなって思います！
Man, I really feel like today's setlist was packed with things Sora-chan loves!
みんなもね、これ歌ってほしいなっていうのを…
And all of you wanted us to sing this...
1曲目は、そらちゃんの好きが詰まったライブでしたね！はい！
The first song was a live packed with Sora-chan's favorites! Yes!
と、ここでね、もう後半なので、えっとね、みんな三人にもちょっと、お、プレゼントチュウ？ なんですか？待ってましたよ！
And so, since we're in the second half now, everyone, the three of us have a little present! What is it? We've been waiting!
お誕生日のグッズを作りましたので、
We made birthday goods, so
ぜひ見ていただけたらと思います！
we hope you'll take a look!
グッズターイム！
Goods time!
それがこちらです！
Here they are!
今年 2022年の
This year, 2022's
記念グッズは2種類です。
anniversary goods come in two types.
フルセットだと B2タペストリー
If you get the full set, the B2 tapestry,
こちらの絵柄ですね。
this is the design.
と マスクとケースになってます！
And it comes with a mask and case!
で 今回は数は少なめなんですけども、
Now, quantities are limited this time,
フルセットで、ええ
but for those who get the full set, um...
手に取ってくださった
For those who managed to get one,
方には、あの直筆サイン入りの
we're planning to include a postcard with a handwritten signature
ポストカード、そして特典ボイスを
and a special bonus voice track.
付けさせていただけたらなと思っております。
We hope you'll look forward to it.
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you very much!
めちゃくちゃ可愛い！
So cute!
ミアスデーにぴったりだな。
It's a great match for Miay's Day.
そうだね、ミアスデーにぴったり！
That's right, it fits Miay's Day perfectly!
え、まずは、一個ずつのやつがあると思うので、それをまずは見ていきたいと思います。
Let's first take a look at the individual items one by one.
こちらです！
Here it is!
こちらが、え、タペストリー。
This here is the tapestry.
おるだん先生の今回のあの配信のジャケットのものをタペストリーにしました！
We made Orudan-sensei's streaming jacket illustration into a tapestry!
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you.
かわいい！
So cute!
めちゃくちゃ猫耳。
Look at those cat ears!
かわいい！
So cute!
お迎えしていただいてありがとうございます。
Thank you so much for picking it up.
そしてマスク＆ケース
As for the mask and case,
の方は、こちらになっておりまして、
it looks like this.
え、シンプルなものにして、いつでも使えるようにと思って色々考えました。
We designed it to be simple so you can use it anytime.
え、あの、ケースの方も
We made the case simple too,
シンプルなものにして、あの、マスクケースとしてだけじゃなくって、
so that instead of just being a mask case,
普段あの学校行く人とか、会社行く人とかには
for those going to school or work,
ペンケースとかとしても使ってもらえたらなみたいな、
you could also use it as a pencil case or for your posts,
なんか日常からシンプルに使えるものと考えました。
something you can easily use in your daily life.
すっごい広く使えるね。
It has so many uses!
いいね。透明な感じになってるんだね、これ。透明な感じになってます。ガンガン使っちゃいましょう。
It has a transparent feel, doesn't it? Let's use it a lot!
あ、なんかまだ、あ、そうか、フルセットの方はタペストリーとマスク＆ケース、
Oh right, the full set includes the tapestry, mask & case,
そしてですね、特典にポストカードと特典ボイスになってるんですが、
and as bonuses, a postcard and special voice!
そのポストカードの方、数量限定の方は全部直筆サインで
For the postcard, all of the limited edition ones will have my handwritten signature.
書かせていただきます。お、早い！そうだね。
Oh, that's fast! That's right.
そしてですね、えっと誕生日記念の、あの、数量限定がなくなっちゃったあとは、
And then, for after the limited edition birthday set runs out...
は、なんだっけ、は、白押し、白押し白押し、白押し、白押し
What was it? Foil-stamped... foil-stamped, foil-stamped...
複製品サイン入りポストカードとなっております。
It'll be a foil-stamped replica signature postcard!
よろしくお願いします！よろしくお願いします！
Thank you very much! Thank you!
そらちゃん、まだ他にも告知することあるんじゃないですか？
Sora-chan, aren't there other announcements?
お疲れだと思うんですけど、頑張って、頑張って。
I'm sure you're tired, but do your best!
ファンクラブから？
From the fan club?
あ、そう、そうなんです。二人人が乗っけてくれる。
Ah, yes, that's right. The two of you are joining in.
えー、ファンクラブを私はやってまして、そちらの方のキャンペーンもあるそうです。こちらです！
I've been running my fan club, and it seems there's a campaign for it too! Here it is!
え、5月31日時点でに、会員になってくださってる方に、
To everyone who is a member as of May 31st,
ご周年記念として、ときのそらオリジナル記念硬貨、風メダルを全員にプレゼント
as a 5th anniversary commemoration, we're giving away Tokino Sora original commemorative wind-medal coins to everyone!
いたします！全員に？全員に？
To everyone?! Yes!
入会でもらえるとのことですので、おねがいいたします。すごいピカピカの金貨とか好きなんだよね。
You can get it just by joining, so please do. I love shiny coins like this as a collector.
コレクターとして、なんか、あの、なんというか、ずっと保存しておけるように
As a collector, I wanted something you could keep and preserve forever.
コレクションできるようなものにしました。一日中眺めるわ、この記念硬貨。
I made it into a collectible item. I'll be staring at this coin all day!
そしてファンクラブの方でもなんと、あの誕生日記念特番放送があります。
And on the fan club side, there will also be a special birthday broadcast!
さらに、そちらの方ですね、スペシャルセッションライブということで、
Furthermore, for that, we'll be having a Special Session LIVE
Elements Gardenの、近藤世真さん、都丸椋太さんと一緒に、
with Elements Garden's Seima Kondo and Ryota Tomaru,
え、一緒に、あのコラボさせていただきまーす！
we'll be doing a collaboration together!
すごい！スペシャルセッションライブ、歌うんですか？
That's amazing! A Special Session LIVE? Will you be singing?
歌もありますし、おしゃべりもしますので、これは見逃せない！ファンクラブに入っている方はぜひ
We'll be singing and chatting, so you won't want to miss this!
お楽しみにしていただけたらうれしいなと思います。
I hope those in the fan club will look forward to it.
え、日付は、え、18日になっております。よろしくお願いします！
The date is set for the 18th. Please look forward to it!
すごい、二人が乗っけてくれたおかげでいっぱい私が喋りそうになったのが抑えられました。
That's amazing, thanks to the two of you joining in, it kept me from talking too much.
特区してできた？特区してできた。ありがとうございます。
Did you get cut off? You got cut off. Thank you!
まだ喋ろうと思ったら、あの、早く早くって言われた。助かりました。
When I thought about talking more, they told me "Hurry, hurry!" That really helped.
じゃ、まだそらちゃんは他にもあるからね。ね。みんな楽しんでいってね！
Well, Sora-chan, there's still more to come, right? Everyone, enjoy yourselves!
二人ともありがとう！がんばって、がんばって。
Thank you both! Do your best!
ありがとう。はい、というわけで、ライブもいよいよ最後の1曲なんですが、
Thank you. Well then, this is finally the last song of the live,
ここでもう一つ最後の、あの、サプライズというか、まだあるんですよ。
but we have one more surprise, there's still more!
なのでそれを見せていきたいと思います。マイク！
So I'd like to show it to you. A microphone!
そして ヘッドフォン！
And headphones!
そして ぬんぬん！
And Nunun!
かわいい！あ、来まっ！
So cute! Ah, wait!
私本当に知らなかったんですよ、ぬんぬんがいるの。ぬんぬん何かプレゼントしてもらっちゃいました！
I really didn't know Nunun was going to be here. Nunun gave me a present!
かわいい！かわいい！ということで、なんか
So cute! So cute! So, um...
みんなからもプレゼントして頂けて
Even receiving presents from everyone,
これで全てのお披露目となりますが、
this completes all the reveals,
まだあるので帰らないで
but there's still more, so don't go home yet.
というわけで、最後の一曲に行こうと思います。
So, I'd like to move on to the final song.
これはもう新曲となりますので聴いていただけると嬉しいです。それでは聞いてください。
Since this is a brand-new song, I'd be happy if you listened to it. Please take a listen.
「空を超えて」
"Beyond the Sky"
私待ってるよ…待ってるよ…待ってるよ…待ってるよ…
I'm waiting... waiting... waiting... waiting...
wow…
Ooh...
張り立てのキャンパスに あなたはまだひとりぼっち
On a freshly stretched canvas, you are still all alone.
1歩目を踏み出して ここから始まったストーリー
Taking your first step, the story began right here.
夢で見た景色は (超満員大アリーナ)
The scenery I saw in my dream—a packed arena
憧れを叶えて！ (青空の向こうへ)
Make your dreams come true! Beyond the blue sky
私待ってるよ待ってるよ待ってるよ この広い舞台で
I'm waiting, waiting, waiting on this vast stage,
あの日からキミがここへたどり着くのを 今歌ってるよ歌ってるよ歌ってるよ
singing right now for the day you finally arrive here since that day.
夢の方へ掛けて きっとどうか届いて！
Reaching toward your dream, I hope it reaches you somehow!
wow…
Ooh...
円卓は広がって 瞬く無数のアステル
The round table expands with countless twinkling asterisms.
夢みたいな色で まだまだ追いかけ続けて
In dreamlike colors, keep chasing on and on.
チャレンジはとまらない (継続的スローペースリーマー)
The challenge never stops (a steady, slow-paced dreamer)
点と点を繋げて (星間線上へ)
Connecting dot to dot (onto the interstellar line)
私待ってるよ待ってるよ待ってるよ 今もずっとここで
I'm waiting, waiting, waiting right here even now,
いつの日かキミが見つけてくれますように ねぇ歌ってるよ歌ってるよ歌ってるよ
hoping you'll find me someday. Hey, I'm singing, singing, singing,
時空間を超えて キミのもとへ届いて！
crossing spacetime to reach your side!
wow…
Ooh...
待ってるよ待ってるよ待ってるよ 時代が変わっても
Waiting, waiting, waiting, even if the era changes,
同じ星が彼方向こうへ飛び立とうとも
even if the same star flies off to distant shores,
寂しくても何度も 歓声を原動力に変えて
even when lonely, turning cheers into fuel time and again.
ここまで歩いてきた私なら…！
As someone who has walked this far...!
私待ってるよ待ってるよ待ってるよ この広い舞台で
I'm waiting, waiting, waiting on this vast stage,
あの日からキミがここへたどり着くのを 今歌ってるよ歌ってるよ歌ってるよ
singing right now for the day you finally arrive here since that day.
目指したあの場所で きっとどうか届いて！ 夢をどうか叶えて！
In that place we aimed for, I hope it reaches you! Make your dream come true!
wow…
Ooh...
最後に、ここでお知らせがあります。
Lastly, I have an announcement to make.
なんと……！
And that is...!
7月20日、アルバムが発売決定……！
My 4th album release is officially decided for July 20th!
4thアルバム「Sign」2022年7月20日にリリース決定です！というこでよろしくお願いします。
My 4th album, 'Sign,' will be released on July 20, 2022! So please look forward to it.
今日最後サプライズだよ。
Today's final surprise!
みんな、ありがとう！
Everyone, thank you!